<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "docbookV4.5/docbookx.dtd"[]>
<section lang="en-EN">
	<title>The short instruction about TaskGen</title>
	<orderedlist>
		<title>Generating variants</title>
		<listitem>
			<para>Fill in the form field <guilabel>Full name</guilabel> Your surname, name and second name, with space, 
   for example: <guilabel>"Иванов Иван Иванович"</guilabel>;</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Choose the theme of lab (conformity can be not total);</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>The description of theme will appear lower, the list of exercises as a buttons, and in window of program - the list of exercises as a text.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Press the exercise-button to open the book of problems at page of that exercise (in some cases - text of exercise).
   In the window of program you can see the description of exercise.</para>
		</listitem>
	</orderedlist>
	<warning><title>Warning!</title><para>The comments in the description of exercise in TaskGen have a higher priority than comments in the book of problems!</para></warning>
<warning><title>Warning!</title><para>Not at all labs you need to complete all 10 exercises - 
  you should ask about it your teacher.</para></warning>
	<formalpara>
		<title>
Updates of exercises database:</title>
		<para>New file <filename>taskgen.sqlite</filename> you should copy with replacement the old one 
  in the working directory of program. In a virtual machine this way <filename>/home/student/.config/taskgen/</filename>.
  You can check updates of database at <ulink url="http://sites.google.com/site/roman7yagodin">http://sites.google.com/site/roman7yagodin</ulink> at section "Программы и компоненты".</para>
	</formalpara>
	<itemizedlist>
		<title>What is not implemented (but in plans):</title>
		<listitem>
			<para>Review of exercises just in TaskGen (требуется перевод задачников 
  в удобный для машинной обработки вид, предположительно в связке 
  DocBook XML + SVG + MathML).</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Разное количество задач по разным темам, возможность задания количества 
  задач, которые требуется решить, в формате "N из M". </para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Integrated exercise editor.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Ранжирование задач по сложности.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Тематическая привязка по каждой задаче (сейчас - по разделу).</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>A special hints for some difficult exercises.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Integrated handbooks of the Physics and the Maths.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Типовые задачи с примерами решения.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Начальные шаблоны для сложных задач.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Модули автоматической проверки результатов.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Update the database of exercises with internet-connection.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Different generation-schemes of the variants.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>База задач олимпиадного уровня.</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
</section>